[{"id": "5ff13fffb0ee8c595b6d3992", "question": "Military leader Napoleon also dabbled in writing what genre of book?", "answer": "Romance", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec23a98dc25ca9e12ef632", "question": "What word describes \"a series of rulers from the same family\"?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7e95fb24f84e0b9f9ffcd", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b69", "question": "What kind of a creature is Hobbes from the comic strip \"Calvin and Hobbes\"?", "answer": "A tiger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97b", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Kuvendi?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65698ae7e414034b5aecd", "question": "When Christopher Columbus sailed to America, what was the first region he arrived in?", "answer": "The Bahamas Archipelago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6e", "question": "Bangladesh is located at the apex of which Bay?", "answer": "Bay of Bengal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e1", "question": "What fruit comes in Redchief and Earliglow variety?", "answer": "Strawberries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910c", "question": "What nationality was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor E. Frankl?", "answer": "Austrian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5e", "question": "How many lines are in a limerick?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81d80d0de9af39e9d468f", "question": "As of 2020, how many times has America officially declared war?", "answer": "11", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bd30fb6c85e9e634ff64", "question": "Who won the World Series in 1987?", "answer": "Minnesota Twins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d9", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trans-Europe Express\"?", "answer": "Kraftwerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c02", "question": "What is actor Jack Nicholson's full birthname?", "answer": "John Joseph Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11b", "question": "Allan Stuart Konigsberg is more famous as who?", "answer": "Woody Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cd", "question": "Who is Freakazoid?", "answer": "Dexter Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339374", "question": "Which \"Saturday Night Fever\" cast member was nominated for an Oscar?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea37c0ff048f679a45ab1d", "question": "What is the rarest blood type?", "answer": "AB negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3e1e44f0f6af5b066645", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 15?", "answer": "Femto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecccbdec223966ae8f88a4", "question": "In what movie did Benedict Cumberbatch wear dentures that were an exact replica of Alan Turing's 60-year old set of false teeth?", "answer": "\"The Imitation Game\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb58dd5dad637d903c8812", "question": "What is Bhutan's national sport?", "answer": "Archery -- It was born out of necessity as bows and arrows were used to repel Tibetans and British invaders in the 19th century.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb67445dad637d903c883c", "question": "What country\u2019s land is mostly on an island, although most of its people live on a peninsula across the South China Sea?", "answer": "Malaysia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d08", "question": "Whose sidekick was named George Fenneman?", "answer": "Groucho Marx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8078ff048f679a45ac19", "question": "What extinct animal was the ancestor of cattle?", "answer": "Auroch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5971e13f89261e916c8e09b3", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba45", "question": "What is the official state dessert of Massachusetts?", "answer": "Boston Cream Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a1", "question": "How tall was the model ape used in the making of the movie \"King Kong\"?", "answer": "18 inches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c849", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the caudate lobe?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's retirement home?", "answer": "Springfield Retirement Castle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f1", "question": "What happens when you roll three consecutive doubles in a game of Monopoly?", "answer": "You go to jail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338889", "question": "Who turned all he touched to gold?", "answer": "King Midas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a120", "question": "Which year did John Schlesinger receive an Academy Award for directing \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d7", "question": "Who traditionally occupied the Peacock Throne?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c2", "question": "Who said of his TV fame: \"To this day, people will call me Dan Arnold.\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2db", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0f", "question": "What is comedian Jon Stewart's full birth name?", "answer": "Jonathan Stuart Leibowitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a968", "question": "What East Coast port is the largest US city to share its name with a British county?", "answer": "Norfolk, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c502fbde8045e48466a5", "question": "What is chionophobia?", "answer": "Fear of snow.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4638ff048f679a45aba0", "question": "The Planting Moon is found in which month?", "answer": "May", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27a", "question": "What is the syrup drained from raw sugar?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be57fc05415ba52ed6f0aae", "question": "What crop is attacked by the Colorado beetle?", "answer": "Potato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51a", "question": "The Banff Airport is located in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a6c890aac110e4167080", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338980", "question": "What disability do both Quasimodo and the judge who sentenced him suffer from in \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Deafness", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6003983057a0e35c43f8389a", "question": "What French painter is credited with inventing the genre of f\u00eates galantes?", "answer": "Antoine Watteau\u00a0-- f\u00eates galantes consists scenes of bucolic and idyllic charm, suffused with a theatrical air.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe0", "question": "What are the hotel-inspired names of the two old men who heckle \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Statler and Waldorf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a3d212f2a7826b9b8729", "question": "What is the atomic number for Palladium?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e3", "question": "What was the first name of Martin Short's character on his TV show \"Primetime Glick\"?", "answer": "Jiminy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec4", "question": "Who was famous for saying \"That's telling like it is\"?", "answer": "Howard Cosell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e04", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Pan?", "answer": "Faunus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba39", "question": "Which US first lady founded a center for the treatment of addictions?", "answer": "Betty Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be5816b5415ba52ed6f0ac1", "question": "What is the study of pronunciation called?", "answer": "Orthoepy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7493a9e54d890926f6fa", "question": "In Texas, it\u2019s illegal to swear in front of what?", "answer": "A corpse", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c16", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the fourth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58be2d418faf425cf37add7c", "question": "The American rock band, \"The Black Keys\", hails from which US state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cc", "question": "Whose execution caused the famed Spanish Armada to sail against England?", "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots'", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbd", "question": "What former sitcom costars play the two lead boys in 2004's \"The Polar Express\" movie?", "answer": "Tom Hanks and Peter Scolari", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab94c586faa38a764be510", "question": "Who bought the rights to manufacture the Isetta in the 1950\u2019s from the Italian company Iso?", "answer": "BMW", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfea99dc5ec6cd98a832b", "question": "What word did Robert A. Heinlein introduce into the English language in his book \"Stranger in a Strange Land\"?", "answer": "In the 1961 science-fiction novel, Heinlein coined the term Grok, which means \"to understand intuitively or by empathy\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c541", "question": "Icthyologists study what?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d47509f8e329de4f8778a3", "question": "What is the capital of Venezuela?", "answer": "Caracas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fd", "question": "What fictional character has a blue box that can travel through time and space?", "answer": "Doctor Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab144ebaab681b09292172", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae86", "question": "What fort did Benedict Arnold promise to surrender to the British, in return for money?", "answer": "West Point", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e08489261e916c8e09ac", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d0fa2596a59cbdfbd384", "question": "What is the common name for a moon that orbits another moon?", "answer": "Moonmoon", "category": "scicence"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339043", "question": "What American playwright titled his autobiography \"Timebends\"?", "answer": "Arthur Miller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef94406ce05a3942286e95", "question": "Where was the game Chinese Checkers originally produced?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600243d44be4723ccac2219c", "question": "Which American writer and poet\u2019s only novel was \"The Bell Jar\"?", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912c", "question": "Dale Arden, Princess Aura, and Dr. Hans Zarkov are characters from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8ce2994b094db915830a5", "question": "At what age did legendary English musician, Lemmy, die in 2015?", "answer": "70", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93dc86bd93ce3a4e5f6b9", "question": "How long is one Pluto year?", "answer": "248 Earth years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9bf", "question": "How many ribs does the typical human body have?", "answer": "24", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad8", "question": "What soft drink, introduced in 1982, was the number three US seller within two years?", "answer": "Diet Coke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec861eec223966ae8f880e", "question": "Renaud Lavillenie and Sergey Bubka are members of what event's exclusive 6-meter-high club?", "answer": "Pole vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7f", "question": "Who was the first black actor to play Shakespeare's Othello on film?", "answer": "Laurence Fishburne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a7", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games after World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8a99901dd7bf43be5e750", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what did the cat take?", "answer": "The rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba88", "question": "Whose death is described in the last chapter of the Torah?", "answer": "Moses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99c6121a8909e5c332d35", "question": "Which band released the album \"Breakfast in America\"?", "answer": "Supertramp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a532", "question": "The Guggenheim Museum is located in what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b0", "question": "What river forms most of the border between the US states Georgia and Alabama?", "answer": "Chattahoochee river", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b89", "question": "What film marked Julie Andrews first starring role?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a545", "question": "What is the capital of the state of Mississippi?", "answer": "Jackson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe734c9eec85e375820b23c", "question": "Who chaired the \"Wannsee Conference\" during World War II?", "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f90", "question": "Which character is the narrator of Melville's \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad76", "question": "Whose tomb was found in the Valley of the Kings in Egypt?", "answer": "Tutankhamun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339962", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what nickname did Milhouse give himself?", "answer": "Thrillhouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bb", "question": "In which decade was the first Vespa scooter manufactured in Italy?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015de71fe83fe1f2a824b6a", "question": "What percent of the casualties in World War II were civilians?", "answer": "60%", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd8", "question": "Who wrote the 1912 novel \"The Lost World\"?", "answer": "Sir Arthur Conan Doyle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d1", "question": "Which bar is said to have given birth to the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919d", "question": "Who was the voice of Donkey in the \"Shrek\" movie series?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b891364247bf200fb882", "question": "The Easter lily is a plant endemic to which Japanese islands?", "answer": "Ryukyu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe37ab70ada16518afdc05b", "question": "What did Nazi Germany use Zyklon B for?", "answer": "To kill people in concentration camps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feb58407e83c707845b20cd", "question": "The Halloween practice of an individual's pocket that has been turned inside out and left to dangle, is aimed at protecting the individual from which hungry creatures?", "answer": "Owls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c23e877e98cb97778987", "question": "The \"nene\" is the official bird of which state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb16", "question": "What number have you rolled in a game of craps, if you roll \"boxcars\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4eaee06d333868d34d75e", "question": "What new economic program did China\u2019s Mao Zedong announce in 1958?", "answer": "\"The Great Leap Forward\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338977", "question": "Who is the last remaining survivor from Earth in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Arthur Dent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b75", "question": "What book tells the story of the Harris family fleeing to Canada to escape slavery?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe77630eec85e375820b318", "question": "What is the world's largest landlocked country?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c5a40775fa611bce67ca", "question": "The spice paprika is made from what?", "answer": "Sweet pepper pods -- Paprika is made from ground sweet pepper pods that are dried and powdered.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fc", "question": "Who played Lester Burnham in \"American Beauty\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d34", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of John and Yoko\"?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bae2364247bf200fb89d", "question": "Which creature's name translates as \"the lizard\" in Spanish?", "answer": "Alligator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c17", "question": "What year was the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" first aired in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab18bdbaab681b0929218e", "question": "Who is the world\u2019s largest tire manufacturer?", "answer": "LEGO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b6", "question": "What movie starring Tobey Maguire and Michael Caine won a Best Adapted Screenplay Oscar for John Irving?", "answer": "The Cider House Rules", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a95120565ad31a57c801", "question": "Xerxes the Great was the king of what empire?", "answer": "Achaemenid Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5f", "question": "In Britain, what kind of meat comes in rashers?", "answer": "Bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a469", "question": "Burkino Faso is a former colony of which European country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a763", "question": "In which US state does the Rio Grande river begin?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66bdba5bfecdd737e088a", "question": "What is the only bird to have its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b839", "question": "What widely celebrated festival is held on the day before Ash Wednesday?", "answer": "Mardi Gras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc0", "question": "What is the \"Big Mac\" that was built in Michigan in 1957?", "answer": "The Mackinac Bridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be4", "question": "What is the name of the controversial novel that was written by Salmon Rushdie?", "answer": "The Satanic Verses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafc", "question": "Which drug can be extracted from the bark of the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ef", "question": "Which classic science fiction author wrote \"The End of Eternity\", \"Pebble in the Sky\", and \"The Caves of Steel\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c902", "question": "What is the fear of nudity known as?", "answer": "Gymnophobia or Nudophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c424", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd54", "question": "The Obie Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Off-Broadway theater", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9a", "question": "Who gave Impressionism its name with his 1873 painting \"Impression, Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600397f857a0e35c43f83899", "question": "What term did the artist Kurt Schwitters invent to describe his works made from scavenged fragments and objects?", "answer": "Father of installation art and a pioneer in fusing collage and abstraction, invented the term\u00a0Merz from the German word\u00a0Kommerz.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae66", "question": "Who was the first woman to be appointed a US Supreme Court Justice?", "answer": "Sandra Day O'Connor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b918e662d71a5365102c", "question": "\"The Color Purple\" begins, \"You better not tell nobody but\" who?", "answer": "God", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942d", "question": "Who played the role of O-Ren Ishii in the 2003 movie \"Kill Bill: Vol. 1\"?", "answer": "Lucy Liu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d8", "question": "What two authors' characters are used to name the moon of Uranus?", "answer": "William Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338938", "question": "What did Fender name the follow up to their \"Telecaster\" guitar?", "answer": "Stratocaster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3f11c73aa70ea0b70afb", "question": "Which Italian region is the source of Marsala wine?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b0", "question": "What nation was led by Sargon the Great?", "answer": "Akkad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7d", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Jack Stanton in the novel \"Primary Colors\"?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e0", "question": "Which famous actress was born Vera Jane Palmer?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d09", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Sodoff Baldrick?", "answer": "Edmund Blackadder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2d", "question": "Suva is the capital of which Melanesian country?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b3704f1c3f17ccc40c8e12", "question": "Which English Member of Parliament referred to the pub as \"the heart of England\"?", "answer": "Samuel Pepys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a296", "question": "Billy Joel's \"Uptown Girl\" music video featured which supermodel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character has a pacemaker?", "answer": "Krusty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b002", "question": "Who was the primary author of the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe36b930ada16518afdc03c", "question": "Which company has employed the largest number of language translators?", "answer": "Google", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164651f9b80650dbe7f926", "question": "What is the capital of India", "answer": "New Delhi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a20", "question": "Who portrayed Michael Corleone's second wife in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae3", "question": "Which French artist, born in 1834 was best known for his paintings of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec722c657c9fcac0ce71977", "question": "What is the name of the traditional song fans sing at the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "\"My Old Kentucky Home\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59774321284458f1d7854425", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339182", "question": "Who was the actor who played Charles in the movie \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\"?", "answer": "Hugh Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dff", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"That's All Folks\"?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e8", "question": "What martial art has a name beginning with \"K\" that means empty hand?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f63", "question": "What actor blogs at \"Schrute-Space\" at NBC.com?", "answer": "Rainn Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb6f877e98cb97778a1a", "question": "In which country are you likely to hear the cheer or toast \"Opa!\" during a celebration?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d9ae308b8581f80b092c0", "question": "While filming a segment for the show \"The Grand Tour\", what car did Richard Hammond crash in June, 2017?", "answer": "Rimac Concept One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87b", "question": "Sinologists study which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac77", "question": "When was the modern tire first introduced to the market?", "answer": "1887", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e95237ccba3ffe45786dc", "question": "Who sang the theme song for the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Jack Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a817", "question": "What city is the fashion center of Italy?", "answer": "Milan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf96f83302ff91e46494", "question": "What are juvenile goats called?", "answer": "Kids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173e6544491cbd7c5a17b0", "question": "The Wright brothers originally ran what kind of business?", "answer": "Bicycle repair and design -- The name of their business was Wright Cycle Company.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a5", "question": "Which planet spins on a nearly horizontal axis?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed3", "question": "Of what nationality was explorer Captain James Cook?", "answer": "British", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95b", "question": "What is the carambola fruit more commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Starfruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc63", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Hot Wheels toy car?", "answer": "1968", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339290", "question": "On the TV show \"Lost\", what group conducts scientific experiments on the island?", "answer": "Dharma Initiative", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc13f5469bb8041d07a082", "question": "Something that is toward the end or away from the center of the body can also be called what?", "answer": "Distal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f30", "question": "Which band member of Thin Lizzy died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Phil Lynott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27c", "question": "Who used hypnotism to treat the hemophilia of Tsarevich Alexei?", "answer": "Rasputin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38f", "question": "What is the nothernmost provincial capital?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada1", "question": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh was better known as who?", "answer": "Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c4", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea31b7ff048f679a45aae3", "question": "What type of rock is obsidian?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73894eec85e375820b264", "question": "What is the driest continent?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb5", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Lasky?", "answer": "Grape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133953d", "question": "Which one of the Salinger brothers developed an alcohol problem on \"Party of Five\"?", "answer": "Bailey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe909bc01dd7bf43be5e891", "question": "Named after the mallow flower, mauve is a shade of what?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2c", "question": "Who is Gwyneth Paltrow's mother?", "answer": "Blythe Danner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca3", "question": "What name was given to people who made illegal booze during prohibition?", "answer": "Moonshiners", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ba", "question": "Which French salad containing tuna, anchovies, tomatoes, olives and hard boiled eggs?", "answer": "Salade nicoise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbba", "question": "During what year's Summer Olympics did swimmer Mark Spitz win seven gold medals?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c212", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fb", "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cd15bb53d1af658864e6", "question": "How many times does the word \"jingle\" appear in the first verse of \"Jingle Bells\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b867", "question": "In which sport do you \"shag\" flies?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b014", "question": "The Orient Express is a train route between what two cities?", "answer": "Paris and Istanbul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c05b", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Panama?", "answer": "Harpy eagle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f700ea9e54d890926f6d4", "question": "South America\u2019s Atacama Desert holds what distinction?", "answer": "Driest non-polar desert -- Although it is home to about one million people, it records less than 1 mm of rain every year.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b5", "question": "Which trio released the album \"CrazySexyCool\"?", "answer": "TLC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b1", "question": "Which country contains Lake Assal, the lowest point on mainland Africa?", "answer": "Djibouti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62c", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"Emerald City\"?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7e2aff048f679a45ac08", "question": "Atychiphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Failure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600395b157a0e35c43f83895", "question": "What prompted Pablo Picasso's famous Blue Period?", "answer": "This period was an artistic response to his depression over the death of Carlos Casagemas,\u00a0a friend who shot himself.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f8", "question": "What instrument is used to measure atmospheric pressure?", "answer": "Barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8b", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Danny in \"City Slickers\"?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bae", "question": "Which Beethoven symphony became associated with victory in WWII?", "answer": "The Fifth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f6", "question": "What sea lies between Greece and Turkey?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b317", "question": "The Canadian Goods and Services Tax came into effect on what date?", "answer": "January 1, 1991", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35a", "question": "Who found the long lost explorer David Livingston?", "answer": "Henry Morton Stanley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b9", "question": "What is a calorie a unit of?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf1", "question": "What is a community of ants called?", "answer": "A colony", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9aa", "question": "What do you call three under par in golf?", "answer": "Albatross or double eagle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c3462b316f4693fb67a7", "question": "Monterey Jack is a type of what?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26578dc25ca9e12ef64a", "question": "How many millimeters are in an inch?", "answer": "25.4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b1be06d333868d34d6d4", "question": "Who commanded the French army in India during the Seven Years War?", "answer": "Dupleix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af57", "question": "Which country do you associate with the Easter Rising?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7668feec85e375820b283", "question": "Al-Azhar, the oldest University in the Arab world, is located in which country?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae92a7574a5ce6b56b8230", "question": "Who wrote the play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c791", "question": "What continent has the highest native population of cheetahs?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8d73ec223966ae8f8854", "question": "The PlayStation prototype was designed by Sony in collaboration with which company?", "answer": "Nintendo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd86fec223966ae8f88dc", "question": "What actor\u2019s face inspired \"Halloween\" baddie Michael Myers\u2019 mask?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c802fbde8045e48466cc", "question": "What is a body's resistance to changes in motion or speed called?", "answer": "Inertia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c19", "question": "Before creating the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\", what was Stephen Hillenburg's occupation?", "answer": "Marine biologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc933e60f0007efaba0e5b", "question": "What is the name of Hopalong Cassidy's horse?", "answer": "Topper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b271", "question": "What did \"Glamorous Glennis\" do on October 19, 1947?", "answer": "Broke the sound barrier for the first time", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523cc5736d4be723796b3a", "question": "Which city is home to the Blue Jays baseball team?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef96796ce05a3942286e9d", "question": "Which U.S. sitcom was the first to use a laugh track?", "answer": "\"The Hank McCune Show\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb016f83302ff91e46498", "question": "Who is often referred to as the \"Fifth Beatle\"?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38d2e1f6c8a670a7957c59", "question": "What is the maximum current of an LASCR (Light Activated Silicon Controlled Rectifier)?", "answer": "3 amps", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14066b0ee8c595b6d399c", "question": "Which 1920s play is the first major play written for children?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65a", "question": "Hall of Fame running back Jim Brown played his entire pro career for which NFL team?", "answer": "Cleveland Browns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b962", "question": "What number shirt did Pele wear?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfde", "question": "How many tournaments make up a Grand Slam in golf?", "answer": "4\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963c", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Prince Philip?", "answer": "Princess Aurora's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce8", "question": "What Christian feast celebrates \"tongues of fire\" descending on the Apostles?", "answer": "Pentecost", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed4", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cf", "question": "On what number is the decimal system based?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef4", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Bigger Thomas?", "answer": "Native Son", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b034", "question": "In what year did Adolf Hitler become Chancellor of Germany?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a2", "question": "What is the largest species of lizard in the world?", "answer": "The komodo dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e8", "question": "What is absent in \"negative\" blood types like O negative and AB negative?", "answer": "Rhesus antigens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984a", "question": "Who played Chad Gates in the 1961 movie \"Blue Hawaii\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d2", "question": "What is stored at a depository in Fort Knox?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a752", "question": "The Black Hills, home to Mount Rushmore, are located in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a680", "question": "Which US state shares a border with the Canadian province of New Brunswick?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad43", "question": "Which country seized the USS Pueblo after accusing its American crew of unlawful spying in 1968?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae02", "question": "Who was the first human in outer space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7e", "question": "What does WD stand for in WD 40?", "answer": "Water Displacement", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35b", "question": "What is a \"kartoffel\" in Hamburg?", "answer": "A potato", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3281ff048f679a45aae7", "question": "How many patents did Thomas Edison accumulate during his lifetime?", "answer": "2332 worldwide (1,093 in the US)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9f", "question": "What Boston Celtic great was nicknamed \"Hondo\"?", "answer": "John Havlicek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6016009afe83fe1f2a824c56", "question": "What was the subject of the first color photograph?", "answer": "A tartan ribbon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937edc208d98002fdd633cb", "question": "What is the name of Beethoven's third symphony?", "answer": "The Eroica", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ec8eb24f84e0b9f9ffe8", "question": "Who originally wrote and performed the song \"Bad Case of Loving You\" that was popularized by Robert Palmer in 1979?", "answer": "Moon Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feb34ab7e83c707845b20cc", "question": "Banknote collectors call it \"banana money\", after its artwork. Which country issued it in some of the territories that it oc\u00adcupied during World War II?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b709", "question": "What is Santa Claus more commonly called in Britain?", "answer": "Father Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5954e9c08e82ccaf3b9a67bc", "question": "What food group is a cucumber technically in?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96b", "question": "What is the only Asian country whose common name is only one syllable?", "answer": "Laos", "category": "geography"}]